hellenicshippingnews.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide

_Last Updated: 24 May 2018, 16:30 UTC_

**Introduction**

Your privacy is important to us and this Privacy Policy provides important information about how Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide (“Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide,” “Site”, “Service”, “we,” “our”, “us”) handle personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to any Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide website, application or service that links to it (collectively, our “Services”).

We have created this privacy policy to guarantee our firm commitment to your privacy and the protection of your information.

If we make changes we consider to be important, we will let you know by placing a notice on the relevant Policy and/or contact you using other methods such as email.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using our website or services or transacting business with us. By using our websites or any of our applications, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**Your consent**

By entering to, connecting to, accessing or using the site and/or service and/or by installing the ” Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide” application you agree to the terms and conditions set forth in this privacy policy (the “Privacy policy”), including to the collection and processing of your personal information (as defined below). If you disagree to any term provided herein, please do not enter to, connect to, access or use the site (including but not limited to the services) in any manner and uninstall the “Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide” application from your device.

**Information We Collect About You**

Generally, we may collect personal information that can identify you, such as your name and email address, and other information that does not identify you.

“Personal Information” means information that can be directly associated with a specific person or entity such as a name or e-mail address, or information about activities directly linked to a person, such as that person’s location. You are not required by law to provide us with any such information, but by using our site and/or services and/or by agreeing to the Terms and/or by using our applications you agree to provide us with such information.

We may collect the following types of data and information from our Users:

**Non-identifiable and anonymous information (“Non-Personal Information”).** Non-Personal Information which we collect consists of technical information and behavioral information, and may include, among other things, type and version of operation system, type of browser, screen resolution, browser and keyboard language, referrer, User’s ‘click-stream’ on the properties and the User’s browsing history (visited pages and dates).

**Individually identifiable information (“Personal Information”)**. This information may identify an individual or may be of a private and/or sensitive nature.

Users who are only visiting our Site do not need to provide any Personal Information.

Users who are interested in the use of our services, such as subscribing to our newsletter, will be required to provide details via the registration form on the Site (namely their name, surname and email address).

If we send you a marketing email, it will include instructions on how to opt out of receiving these emails in the future.

Surveys and polls: If you choose to participate in a survey or poll, any personal information you provide may be used for marketing or market research purposes.

**Information collected automatically**. We automatically collect information from your browser when you visit our website. This information includes your IP address, your browser type and language, access times, the content of any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us (see “Cookies” below), and the referring website address.

**Cookies**. When you visit our website, we may assign your computer one or more cookies, to facilitate access to our site and to personalize your online experience. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our website. You may also clear or delete existing cookies from standard internet browsers. For more information on cookies, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/cookie-policy/).

**How we collect information from you**

We use the following methods to collect information:

**Non-personal information**. We collect this information through your use of the Site and/or Service. When you are use the Site and/or Service we may gather, collect and record the information relating to such usage.

**Personal information which you provide us voluntarily**. We collect this information when you subscribe to our newsletter by completing the registration form. We also collect information when you contact us for any reason. We store the personal information either independently or through the help of our authorized third-party service providers (See section “Third Party Software/Service” below).

**Information Use**

What do we do with the information we gather about you?

  *  allow users to use the Site and/or Service, including in their applications
  * perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our services, or content, or services or content offered by others
  * collect information for statistical and research purposes and for the customization and improvement of the Service and/or Site.
  * allow us to contact the registered Users
  * ensuring the security of our website and services
  * maintaining back-ups of our databases
  * develop and display content and advertising tailored to your interests on our site and other sites
  * enforce our terms and conditions
  * manage our business
  * perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection

In more detail:

**Analitycs**

We use Google Analytics to monitor and analyze web traffic and to keep track of User behavior in order to improve the Service. For more information see our “Cookies used by our service providers” section.

**Relevant Advertising**

We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on the Service to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer’s experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We disclose information to third parties only in aggregate or de-identified form. The third-party we use for this service is Google AdSense. For more information see our “Cookies used by our service providers” section.

**Contact Form**

By filling in the contact form on our website with their data, the user gives permission to the Site to use this data to reply to requests for information, inquiries or any other form of request as indicated by the form’s header. The data collected is: name, surname, email address.

**Email Newsletters**

Hellenic Shipping News Worlwide sends you email newsletters or promotional email about services offered by Hellenic Shipping News Worlwide and its advertisers.

We will not send you email if you have opted out. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by either (1) following the “Subscribe / Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email we send, or (2) you can email us at [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com) with your request and the email address it concerns. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address for commercial purposes without your permission. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact [info@hellenicsippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicsippingnews.com). To manage your contact details, please click the “change your contact details” option at the bottom of each email we send.

**Emails From You**

If you send us an email, we will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

**Our policy regarding sharing and usage**

We will never share, sell, or rent individual personal information to/with anyone without your advance permission unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is only available a) to employees managing this information for the purpose of contacting you regarding your subscription or a request made by you for information, or b) to contracted service providers for the purpose of providing services relating to our communications with you.

**Third Parties**

**Third-Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to information that we collect from you. There are a number of places on our website or through our services which may direct your internet browser to a third party website or a portion of the Site controlled by a third party (typically through the use of a frame or pop-up window separate from other content on our Site) that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. For example, if you click on an advertisement on our website, you may be taken to a website that we do not control. Disclosure of personal information to such third party shall be subject to the terms of such third party’s privacy policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policy or content of web sites that we do not own, even if such a site is linked on our Site. We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the “privacy” link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

When you share or recommend links to content on a third-party platform (such as Facebook, Google+ and Twitter), that action and any information you share will be covered by their privacy policy.

**Third Party Software/Service**

While using the Site and/or Service we may be using third party software and/or service, in order to collect, store and/or process the information detailed herein. Such software/service include without limitation, Google Analytics (http://www.google.com/analytics/).

Personal information will be made available to these parties only when necessary to fulfill the services they provide to us, such as software, system, and platform support; direct marketing services; cloud hosting services; advertising; and data analytics;. Our third-party service providers are not permitted to share or use personal information we make available to them for any other purpose than to provide services to us.

We collaborate with third parties such as cloud hosting services and technology support located around the world to serve the needs of our business, workforce, and customers. We take appropriate steps to ensure that personal information is processed, secured, and transferred according to applicable law.

When you provide personal information through our website, the information may be sent to servers located in the United States and other countries around the world. We may share your personal information with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions such as supporting our website functionality, and supporting newsletter services and other features offered through our website, but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes. You can also review and update your personal information by contacting us at [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com).

Any third parties to whom we may disclose personal information may have their own privacy policies which describe how they use and disclose personal information. Those policies will govern use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. If you want to learn more about their privacy practices, we encourage you to visit the websites of those third parties. These entities or their servers may be located either inside or outside the United States.

**Third parties for legal reasons**

We may be required to use and retain personal information for legal and compliance reasons, such as the prevention, detection, or investigation of a crime; loss prevention; or fraud. We may also use personal information to meet our internal and external audit requirements, information security purposes, and as we otherwise believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, which may include laws outside your country of residence; (b) to respond to requests from courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, and other public and government authorities, which may include such authorities outside your country of residence; (c) to enforce our terms and conditions; and (d) to protect our rights, privacy, safety, or property, or those of other persons. We also may disclose your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**Security**

Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide takes great care in implementing and maintaining your security and uses reasonable efforts to help safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they may do so only for permitted business functions and we use firewalls to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information.

We want you to feel confident using Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide. However, no system can be completely secure and we cannot guarantee that your personal information will be absolutely protected. Therefore, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure. For example, your personal information may be affected by actions outside of our control, such as computer “hacking” and physical theft. Users should also take care with how they handle and disclose their personal information and should avoid sending personal information through insecure email. You acknowledge that you provide your personal information at your own risk.

Please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this privacy policy.

**Cookies and Local Storage**

When You access or use the Site and/or Service, we may use industry-wide technologies, such as cookies, which stores certain information on your computer (“Local Storage”) and which will allow us to enable automatic activation of certain features, and make your experience much more convenient and effortless. Most browsers will allow You to erase cookies from your computer’s hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. We may also use certain third-party cookies. These are a different kind of cookies, stored on your computer by third parties, rather than by Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide. This kind of cookie is only read (and not altered by the Site) each time you visit the Site, and also when you visit certain websites or applications that use similar cookies. Third-party cookies usually store only Non-personal Information, such as the web pages you have visited, the duration of your browsing, etc.

**Cookies used by our service providers**

Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the internet.

You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>.

For more information on cookies, please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/cookie-policy/) page.

**Your right to access and correct your personal information**

We respect your right to access and control your information, and we will respond to requests for information and, where applicable, will correct, amend, or delete your personal information.

**Access to personal information** : If you request access to your personal information, we will gladly comply, subject to any relevant legal requirements and exemptions, including identity verification procedures. Before providing data to you, we will ask for proof of identity and sufficient information about your interaction with us so that we can locate any relevant data. We may also charge you a fee for providing you with a copy of your data (except where this is not permissible under local law).

**Correction and deletion** : In some jurisdictions, you have the right to correct or amend your personal information if it is inaccurate or requires updating. You may also have the right to request deletion of your personal information. Remember that you can update your contact information by using the “change your contact details” option at the bottom of each email we send.

**Marketing preferences** : If, at any time, you prefer not to receive emails from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email, or email us at [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com) with your request and the email address it concerns. Information related to controlling cookies can be found [here](https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/cookie-policy/). If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com) and provide your email address so we can remove it from the mailing list.

**Filing a complaint** : If you are not satisfied with how Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide manages your personal data, you have the right to make a complaint to a data protection regulator. A list of National Data Protection Authorities can be found here: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

If you have any requests related to your personal information, please contact us at: [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com).

**Why did I receive an email from you?**

If you received a mailing from us, either a) your email address is listed with us as belonging to someone who has expressly requested receipt of information in the future (‘opt-in’), or b) you have registered with, purchased from or otherwise have an existing relationship with us.

**Children’s Privacy**

Our website is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18.

**Changes of the Privacy Policy**

Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. You are encouraged to check and revisit this page as often as you wish to update yourself with any changes. If you have any questions regarding this policy or do not feel that your concerns have been addressed, please direct your questions to: [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com)

When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the “Last Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending an email to the email address you most recently provided us.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please contact us by email at: [info@hellenicshippingnews.com](mailto:info@hellenicshippingnews.com)

Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide

©2018 Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide. All rights reserved.
